<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community-rsses on Learn to Code Grand Rapids</title>
    <link>http://ltcgr.com/community/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community-rsses on Learn to Code Grand Rapids</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://ltcgr.com/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>http://ltcgr.com/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ltcgr.com/community/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are very lucky to have such a thriving tech community in West Michigan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-connected&#34;&gt;Get Connected&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;slack&#34;&gt;Slack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the Grand Rapids Slack server you will find many tech channels, including one for this group (#learn-to-code). Here you can interact with other living, breathing humans in our area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slackin-grandrapids.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;Sign up&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://grandrapids.slack.com&#34;&gt;Login&lt;/a&gt; if you already have an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conga&#34;&gt;Conga&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conga provides an aggregated calendar for tech events happening in the area. This list is managed by people so if your favorite meetup is not listed contact the organizer to get it on the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://conga-wm.org/calendar/&#34;&gt;View the Conga calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-involved&#34;&gt;Get Involved&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[bitcamp]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conferences&#34;&gt;Conferences&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-dev-day-night&#34;&gt;GR Dev Day / Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;glsec&#34;&gt;GLSEC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;big-data-ignite&#34;&gt;Big Data Ignite&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;kalamazoo-x&#34;&gt;Kalamazoo X&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;barcamp&#34;&gt;BarCamp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;grcon&#34;&gt;GrCon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;meetups&#34;&gt;Meetups&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;big-data-and-hadoop-users-group-of-west-michigan-http-www-meetup-com-big-data-and-hadoop-users-group-of-west-michigan&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Big-Data-and-Hadoop-Users-Group-of-West-Michigan/&#34;&gt;Big Data and Hadoop Users Group of West Michigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a call to data scientists, analysts, architects, and developers. Big Data has become more than vaporware. Companies like Cloudera and Hortonworks have been working hard on improving Big Data technologies; they are now enterprise ready. Join us as we embark on a journey to learn about the toolset, use cases, and common implementation scenarios of Hadoop and other technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;devops-west-michigan-http-www-meetup-com-devops-west-michigan&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/DevOps-West-Michigan/&#34;&gt;DevOps West Michigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DevOps West Michigan is a MeetUp group for people interested in learning about and sharing DevOps principles and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;embedded-gr-http-www-meetup-com-embedded-gr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/embedded-gr/&#34;&gt;Embedded GR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Embedded GR is a group of engineers, hobbyists, students, and managers in the Grand Rapids, MI area. We discuss the development, tooling, and processes associated with the creation of embedded systems. Whether you are interested in programming microcontrollers, designing circuits, or managing complex engineering systems, you&amp;rsquo;ll find ways we can learn from one another and share our experiences in this community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gamedevgr-http-www-meetup-com-gamedevgr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/GamedevGR/&#34;&gt;GameDevGR&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a group for anyone interested in video game development. All skill levels (gamer, beginner, expert, etc.) and all skill sets (programmer, artist, animator, writer, sound designer, etc.) are welcome. I started this group to meet others who are enthusiastic about making games and want to learn from each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;girl-develop-it-grand-rapids-https-www-meetup-com-girl-develop-it-grand-rapids&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Girl-Develop-It-Grand-Rapids/&#34;&gt;Girl Develop It Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Women Developers and Programmers! Want to learn how to code? Have a great idea? Don&amp;rsquo;t be shy. Develop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be intimidating for women to learn and ask questions when they are in an extreme minority. While open and welcoming, today&amp;rsquo;s budding developer community is up to 91% male. There isn&amp;rsquo;t a comfortable place where women can learn at their own pace and not be afraid to ask &amp;ldquo;stupid questions.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided it was time to provide a place where all questions are OK and everyone can learn in a supportive environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-cocoaheads-https-www-meetup-com-gr-cocoa-heads&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/GR-Cocoa-Heads/&#34;&gt;GR CocoaHeads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CocoaHeads is a group devoted to discussion of Apple Computer&amp;rsquo;s Cocoa and CocoaTouch Frameworks for programming on MacOS X and iOS. During monthly meetings, members present on their projects and offer tutorials on various programming topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-drupal-users-http-www-meetup-com-grupal&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/grupal/&#34;&gt;GR Drupal Users&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drupal users, site builders, and developers from the Grand Rapids, MI area get together to discuss a wide range of topics related to the content management system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-functional-programming-http-www-meetup-com-grand-rapids-functional-programming-group&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Grand-Rapids-Functional-Programming-Group/&#34;&gt;GR Functional Programming&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a group for anyone interested in functional programming, whether it&amp;rsquo;s pure functional languages like Haskell, impure functional languages like Clojure, or languages like Python and Ruby which have the capabilities. All levels of experience and interest are welcome, and hopefully we can foster passion for functional programming in Grand Rapids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-issa-http-www-gr-issa-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gr-issa.org/&#34;&gt;GR ISSA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GR-ISSA is a local chapter of the international Information Systems Security Association (or ISSA) based in Grand Rapids, Michigan. GR-ISSA provides local security professionals and practitioners a variety of information security resources ranging from presentations and knowledge sharing to social networking opportunities. This site is dedicated to the Grand Rapids, Michigan chapter of ISSA. GR-ISSA was founded in 2003. For information about the parent international ISSA organization, you are encouraged to visit www.issa.org.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-it-professionals-spicecorps-https-www-meetup-com-grand-rapids-it-professionals-spicecorp&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Grand-Rapids-IT-Professionals-SpiceCorp/&#34;&gt;GR IT Professionals [SpiceCorps]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone in IT or has passion for computers and technology are welcome! We will meetup monthly to discuss the latest and greatest in Information Technology over beers, vent about our latest projects and needy users, and do prizes where we give away SWAG from SpiceWorks and sponsors!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-java-users-group-http-www-meetup-com-gr-jug&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/gr-jug/&#34;&gt;GR Java Users Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join other local Java developers to learn more about Java, the JVM, and related technologies and languages. We encourage you to share what you know by volunteering to present a topic, too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-powershell-user-group-https-grposh-github-io&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://grposh.github.io/&#34;&gt;GR Powershell User Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a local group from Grand Rapids, Michigan, and surrounding areas. We meet monthly to discuss and expand our knowledge of Windows PowerShell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-python-users-group-http-www-meetup-com-grpython&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/grpython/&#34;&gt;GR Python Users Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a certified Pythonista or just curious about getting started with the Python programming language, join us on the third Monday of each month at The Factory in Grand Rapids, Michigan for our regular meetings. We usually have a presentation or group discussion, and all attendees are welcome to ask questions, suggest topics, or present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-salesforce-developer-group-http-www-meetup-com-grand-rapids-salesforce-developer-group&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Grand-Rapids-Salesforce-Developer-Group/&#34;&gt;GR Salesforce Developer Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Connect with local developers building on the AppCloud! Learn from others and share your knowledge with the group!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-testers-http-www-meetup-com-gr-testers&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/GR-Testers/&#34;&gt;GR Testers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re a bunch of software testers. We like to get together over a meal and talk about testing and general geekery. We meet sometime in the 2nd or 3rd week of the month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gr-web-development-http-www-meetup-com-grwebdev&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/grwebdev/&#34;&gt;GR Web Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a group of web developers in the Grand Rapids, MI area. We discuss all parts of developing for the web, from HTML, CSS, and Javascript to design, user experience, usability, accessibility, and tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;internet-of-things-west-michigan-http-www-meetup-com-internet-of-things-west-michigan-iotwm&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Internet-of-Things-West-Michigan-IoTWM/&#34;&gt;Internet of Things, West Michigan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet of Things (IoT) is the next frontier in information technology, enabling automation and intelligence in common objects, like cars, homes and even appliances in our homes. This group is for anyone who is excited about interconnecting devices or leveraging data collected from these devices to gain further knowledge or competitive advantage. This is a call to entrepreneurs, technologists, scientists, engineers, designers, researchers, and students, as well as anyone who is simply curious, to get together and delve into IoT by way of discussion, presentation, and even working together on cool projects! Who knows… we may just change the future!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ixda-grand-rapids-http-www-meetup-com-ixdagr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/IxDAGR/&#34;&gt;IxDA Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IxDA Grand Rapids is a local chapter of the IxDA—the global professional network. We provide opportunities &amp;amp; platforms to gather &amp;amp; advance the discipline of interaction design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ladies-that-ux-grand-rapids-http-www-meetup-com-ladies-that-ux-grand-rapids&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Ladies-That-UX-Grand-Rapids/&#34;&gt;Ladies that UX Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who are the Ladies that UX, you ask? We are a collaborative community of UX designers, technical, and creative professionals from the Grand Rapids area looking to inform West Michigan (and the world!) of the impact of ladies working in our industry. Through UX and design-focused events and meet-ups we encourage our members to engage in meaningful conversations, network with other local professionals, and develop new insights into UX processes and practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;learn-to-code-grand-rapids-https-www-meetup-com-learn-to-code-grand-rapids&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Learn-To-Code-Grand-Rapids/&#34;&gt;Learn to Code Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our group. Come join us at our next meetup!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;software-gr-and-glsec-https-www-meetup-com-software-gr-and-glsec&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Software-GR-and-GLSEC/&#34;&gt;Software GR and GLSEC&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded by Atomic Object in the fall of 2003, SoftwareGR is a 501c6 non-profit trade association dedicated to improving the competitiveness of Michigan’s software development community. We are interested in all aspects of software, from design and development, to testing and user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-west-michigan-cisco-user-group-http-www-wmcug-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wmcug.org/&#34;&gt;The West Michigan Cisco User Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Michigan Cisco User Group (WMCUG) is a non-profit, independent users group which is dedicated to the open exchange of information in the fields of internetworking and the advanced technologies that support the business goals of an organization. WMCUG focus will primarily, but not exclusively be devoted to Cisco products and solutions. Within this framework, we build a community to share best practices and provide a forum for members to grow as individual contributors in the technology arena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-cloud-computing-http-www-meetup-com-west-michigan-cloud-computing&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/West-Michigan-Cloud-Computing/&#34;&gt;West Michigan Cloud Computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Michigan Cloud Computing (WMCC) group is an informal gathering of individuals with a focus on discussing cloud computing from various perspectives. We welcome people from all domains and experience levels to come and share their knowledge and best practices, drive innovation by exchanging ideas and network in the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-content-strategy-meetup-http-www-meetup-com-content-strategy-west-michigan&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/Content-Strategy-West-Michigan/&#34;&gt;West Michigan Content Strategy Meetup&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are hundreds of Content Experts in West Michigan. At times, the many options for networking ends up reinforcing the silos we are constrained by in our professional settings. In an effort to disrupt the status quo, we are creating a generalist group for anyone to talk about the challenges, successes, and learned lessons we all experience with our clients, peers, and competitors as we create, deliver, manage, govern, distribute, and preserve content. Presenters could be our peers as well as guest thought leaders sharing their expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-linux-users-group-http-www-wmlug-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wmlug.org/&#34;&gt;West Michigan Linux Users&amp;rsquo; Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WMLUG&amp;rsquo;s goal is to provide a friendly atmosphere to learn about using Linux and open-source software for the home and enterprise user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-network-technology-users-group-http-www-wmntug-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wmntug.org/&#34;&gt;West Michigan Network Technology Users Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Michigan Network Technology Users Group, or WMNTUG is an organization comprised of computer professionals dedicated to advancing awareness and education in the use of &amp;ldquo;Network Technology&amp;rdquo; and related applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-r-users-group-https-www-meetup-com-west-michigan-r-users-group&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/West-Michigan-R-Users-Group/&#34;&gt;West Michigan R Users Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a place for anyone interested in the open source statistical software R and its associated tools and variations such as RStudio, ShinyR, Revolutions R Open, SparkR and others. R is one of the fastest growing tools in the data scientist&amp;rsquo;s toolbox providing visualization and statistical analysis capability. We will discuss R programming, statistical techniques using R, finding help with R, R packages (add-ons) and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;west-michigan-ruby-users-group-http-www-meetup-com-mi-ruby&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/mi-ruby/&#34;&gt;West Michigan Ruby Users Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meet other local Ruby programmers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;wordpress-grand-rapids-http-www-meetup-com-wpgrandrapids&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/wpgrandrapids/&#34;&gt;WordPress Grand Rapids&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A group for anyone interested in WordPress, whether it&amp;rsquo;s blogging with WordPress, developing with/for WordPress, or running a business based around WordPress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>